Guide to the Erich Maria Remarque Papers MSS.095
Fales Library and Special Collections
Erich Maria Remarque Papers
1893-1990
Fales Library and Special Collections
Remarque, Erich Maria, 1898-1970
Goddard, Paulette, 1911-1990
MSS.095
89.5 Linear Feet in 113 manuscript boxes, 6 half manuscript boxes, 4 card boxes, 20 oversized flat boxes, 3 box binders, 3 oversized folders, 1 film can, 2 record cartons, 1 LP box, and 2 tall manuscript boxes.
Erich Maria Remarque (1898-1970) was a German-born novelist and screenwriter, best known for All Quiet On the Western Front. The collection contains manuscripts and articles written by Remarque, correspondence, personal documents, photographs, clippings, and memorabilia. The collection also includes some materials created by his wife Paulette Goddard.
Provenance
Remarque's papers were transferred by Paulette Goddard to New York University beginning in 1977.
Accretions were transferred between 1993 and 2000 from the offices of Richard Kay, who served as a legal and financial advisor to Paulette Goddard. Many of the documents appear to have previously come from the offices of Harriet Pilpel, Erich Remarque's attorney and friend.
Scope and Content
The papers of Erich Maria Remarque document his work as a writer: the collection contains manuscripts of his novels, screenplays, scripts, poetry and articles dating from the 1910s until his death in 1970, as well as correspondence related to the publication and publicity of his work. Additionally, the collection is also made up of personal materials related to Remarque, including correspondence, medical documentation, horoscopes, vital records, photographs, memorabilia, and diaries. There are also extensive clipping files as a part of the collection, both related to articles in newspapers and magazines on Remarque as well on topics that pertained to his interests that he wrote about in his novels, such as World War I and II, automobiles, celebrity culture, and other topics on Europe.
Remarque was also an art collector, the collection also consists of correspondence with art dealers and reproductions of art, as well as lists of what art was in his art collection. There is also a significant amount of material in the collection related to his life in Porto Ronco, Switzerland with his wife Paulette Goddard, who was an actress and socialite.
Arrangement
The series is arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Manuscripts
Series 2: Writings in Print
Series 3A: Correspondence from Remarque
Series 3B: Correspondence to Remarque
Series 3C: Correspondence with Attached Manuscripts
Series 3D: Field Correspondence
Series 3E: Envelopes
Series 4A: Diaries
Series 4B: Address books and notebooks
Series 4C: Calling Cards
Series 4D: Notes and lists
Series 5: Drawings
Series 6A: Personal Documents
Series 6B: Medical Documents and Correspondence
Series 6C: Astrology Documents and Correspondence
Series 6D: Financial and Business Correspondence
Series 6E: Correspondence with Agents
Series 6F: Correspondence with Publishers
Series 7A: Photographs
Series 7B: Portraits
Series 8A: Printed Materials about Remarque (Clippings)
Series 8B: Printed Materials about Remarque (Full Copies)
Series 9A: Material collected by Remarque (Clippings)
Series 9B: Material collected by Remarque (Full Copies)
Series 10A: Art Collecting Materials
Series 10B: Art and Auction Catalogs
Series 11: Memorabilia
Series 12: Paulette Goddard
Series 13: Music
Series 14: 2003 Accretion
Biographical Note
Novelist Erich Maria Remarque was born on June 22, 1898 in Osnabrück, Germany. He spent his childhood in imperial Osnabrück, and later served in the German army in World War I on the Western Front. Remarque's books were burned and banned in Nazi Germany, and he lived in exile in Switzerland and the United States following the revocation of his German citizenship in 1938. Remarque married, divorced, and remarried Ilse Jutta Zambona. In 1958 he married American actress Paulette Goddard, and they remained married until his death.
Remarque is best known for his novel All Quiet On the Western Front, which was first published in 1929. His other published novels include The Road Back (1931), Three Comrades (1936), Flotsam (1941), Arch of Triumph (1945), The Black Obelisk (1956), Heaven Has No Favorites (1961), and The Night in Lisbon (1962). Many of these works were adapted into films, often shortly after their publication. According to the Erich Maria Remarque-Peace Center, Remarque critically examined German history in his works, upholding "the preservation of human dignity and humanity in times of oppression, terror and war." Remarque died on September 25, 1970 in Locarno, Switzerland.
Sources: http://www.remarque.uni-osnabrueck.de/internet.htm
http://remarque.org/about_remarque.html
Related Materials
Paulette Goddard Papers (MSS 197)
Fales Manuscript Collection (MSS 001) (contains Goethe manuscripts believed to have belonged to Erich Remarque)
Julie Gilbert Papers (MSS 038)
New American Library Archive (MSS 070)
Separated Materials
The following books were removed to be catalogued:
Erich Maria Remarque Jahrbuch/Yearbook I (1991)
Pirchan, Emil. Buehnen Brevier.
Reue ist undeutsch.
Spoto, Donald. Blue Angel. (1992)
Marlene Dietrich's ABC (1962)
Inscribed to "Mein lieber Alfred" signed "Tante Lena" - Marlene by Marlene Dietrch (1989)
Man Kann alten Dreck nicht vergraben, er fängt immer wieder an zu stinken: Materialien zu einem Erich Maria Remarque-Projekt der Universität Osnabrück, Fachbereich Sprache, Literatur, Medien und zu der Inszenierung der Probebühne Der schwarze Obelisk, eine Textkollage [herausgegeben von Lothar Schwindt und Tilman Westphalen]..
Der schwarze Obelisk: eine Textkollage: Stück in 36 Bildern nach dem gleichnamigen Roman und unter Verwendung anderer Romane Erich Maria Remarques sowie von Originaldokumenten / erarbeitet auf der Grundlage des Entwurfs einer Bühnenfassung "Der schwarze Obelisk, Geschichte einer verspäteten Jugend" in drei Teilen von Hans Jürgen Meyer durch eine Projektgruppe der Universität Osnabrück, Fachbereich Sprache, Literatur, Medien im WS 1982/83 und SS 1983, Harald Keller ... [et al.]; Endredaktion, Tilman Westphalen.
Krieg und Literatur
Sekundärmaterial in Auswahl
Erich Maria Remarque ein Weltbürger wider Willen (partly in Russian)
Mitteilungen der Erich Maria Remarque Gesellschaft Osnabrueck E.V. Heft 4 September 1988
Erich Maria Remarque: der Weg Zurück: eine Ausstellung / [herausgegeben vom Vorstand der Erich Maria Remarque Gesellschaft e.V., Osnabrück; in Zusammenarbeit mit dem Erich Maria Remarque Archiv/Forschungsstelle Krieg und Literatur, Universität Osnabrück; Bild- und Textredaktion: Brigitte Jorden-Kellermeier und Detlef Vornkahl; in Zusammenarbeit mit Thomas Schneider; Kataloggestaltung und Ausstellungsdesign: Michael Fischer.
Das Erich Maria Remarque-Archiv Osnabrück / [herausgegeben vom Erich Maria Remarque-Archiv/Forschungsstelle Krieg und Literatur im Auftrag von Stadt und Universität Osnabrück; Redaktion: Claudia Glunz].
The Hurrell Style: 50 Years of Photographing Hollywood
What becomes a Legend most?: The Blackgama Story by Peter Rogers
with inscription to Paulette from author
Savini un nome nella storia
Conditions Governing Access
Series 6B is closed due to privacy concerns. The rest of the collection is open to researchers.
Other Finding Aids
An item level German language inventory for Series 1-11 is available from the Fales Library. Please contact special.collections@nyu.edu for further assistance.
Personal correspondence.; Paperbacks.; Novels.; Novelists, German -- 20th century; Paperbacks -- Publishing -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Paintings (visual works); New York (N.Y.).; German Americans -- Ethnic identity; Financial records; Briefs (legal documents); Booksellers and bookselling; Black-and-white negatives.; Black-and-white photographs.; Authors and publishers.; Art -- Collectors and collecting.; Art objects -- Collectors and collecting.; Appointment books.; Administrative records; Actresses -- United States; Acting; Accounts; business records; Collectors and collecting.; Motion picture plays.; Motion pictures.; Marginalia (annotations); Motion picture actors and actresses.; Manuscripts; Manuscripts for publication.; Literature publishing -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Manuscript preparation (Authorship).; Legal documents.; Literary agents.; Law -- New York (State) -- History; Legal correspondence.; Hollywood (Los Angeles, Calif.); Law -- United States -- History; German Americans -- New York (State) -- New York; Holocaust.; Literature, Modern -- Translations; Writings (document genre); Theater.; Theatrical publishing.; Tax returns.; Television plays.; Fiction -- 20th century; Editor author correspondence.; Editing; Drama.; Drafts (documents); Datebooks.; Correspondence.; Contracts; Tax records.; Publishers and publishing -- United States -- Correspondence; Publishers and publishing; Postcards.; Photographs.; Personal papers.; Film.; Film stills.; Goddard, Paulette, 1911-1990; Pilpel, Harriet F.
- Series 1: Manuscripts, 1916-1987; 15.25 Linear Feet in 34 manuscript boxes and 1 half manuscript box.
  Scope and Contents
  This series mostly contains handwritten and typed drafts of Remarque's novels, poems, essays, articles, scripts, and other writings. Outlines, notes, and clippings pertaining to the writings are also in the series.
  - Die Traumbude / The Dream Room -- copy, 1920 (Box 104, Folder 1, Item 1-2)
  - Die Traumbude / The Dream Room -- translation (clean copy), 1987 (Box 104, Folder 2, Item 1-2)
  - Die Traumbude / The Dream Room -- annotations, 1920 (Box 104, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front -- film script (clean copy), 1929 (Box 104, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front -- film script (clean copy), 1929 (Box 104, Folder 4, Item 1)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front -- notes, circa 1929 (Box 104, Folder 5, Item 1)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front -- working manuscript, 1928 (Box 104, Folder 5, Item 2)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front -- working manuscript, 1920s (Box 104, Folder 6, Item 1)
  - Der Kampf um Remarque -- copy, 1929 (Box 104, Folder 7, Item 1)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front -- playscript, undated (Box 104, Folder 7B)
  - Im Westen nichts Neues / All Quiet on the Western Front -- film advertising brochure, 1979 (Box 104, Folder 8, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 9, Item 1-4)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 9, Item 5-6)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 9, Item 7)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 10, Item 1-2)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 10, Item 3)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 10, Item 4)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 10, Item 5)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 10, Item 6-7)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 10, Item 8-9)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 11, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 11, Item 2)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 12, Item 1-2)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 13, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 14, Item 1-2)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 15, Item 1-2)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 105, Folder 16, Item 1-5)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 17, Item 1-2)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 18, Item 1-7)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 19, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 20, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 20, Item 2)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- themes, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 20, Item 3)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 21, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- outline and synopsis, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 21, Item 2)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 22, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- character list, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 22, Item 2)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 22, Item 3)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 22, Item 4-8)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 23, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 23, Item 2-6)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- synopsis, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 23, Item 7)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- plan, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 23, Item 8-9)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 23, Item 10-13)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 23, Item 14-15)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 24, Item 1-2)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 1-4)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 5-7)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 8-9)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 10)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- synopsis, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 11)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 12)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- outline, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 13)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 14)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- annotated outline, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 15)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 16)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- plan, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 17)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 18-20)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 21)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- newspaper clippings, 1928 (Box 106, Folder 25, Item 22)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 107, Folder 26, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- newspaper clipping, 1930 (Box 107, Folder 27, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript, circa 1931 (Box 107, Folder 27, Item 2-7)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 54, Folder 28, Item 1)
  - Der Weg zurück / The Road Back -- working manuscript notes, circa 1931 (Box 54, Folder 28, Item 2)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 29, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 29, Item 2)
  - Jugendroman notes, undated (Box 107, Folder 30, Item 1-2)
  - Personal notes, undated (Box 107, Folder 30, Item 3)
  - Pat -- notes, circa 1932 (Box 107, Folder 30, Item 4)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 30, Item 5)
  - Pat -- working manuscript, circa 1932 (Box 107, Folder 30, Item 6)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 30, Item 7)
  - Pat -- working manuscript, circa 1932 (Box 107, Folder 30, Item 8-15)
  - Pat -- working manuscript, circa 1932 (Box 107, Folder 31, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 1-3)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 4-5)
  - Pat -- working manuscript, circa 1932 (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 6)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 7)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 8-10)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript material, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 11)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 12-14)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- newspaper clippings, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 15)
  - Notes for a Garbo Film, undated (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 16)
  - "Der Mann, der die Zeit bekriegte" -- notes, undated (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 17)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 18-20)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 32, Item 21-22)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 33, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 107, Folder 33, Item 2)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- synopsis and scene outline, circa 1936 (Box 54, Folder 34, Item 1)
  - Pat -- clean copy, circa 1932 (Box 54, Folder 34, Item 2)
  - Pat -- clean copy, circa 1932 (Box 54, Folder 35, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 54, Folder 35, Item 2)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 54, Folder 36, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 54, Folder 37, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 54, Folder 38, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 54, Folder 39, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 54, Folder 39, Item 2)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 40, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 41, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 42, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 43, Item 1)
  - Pat -- working manuscript, circa 1932 (Box 55, Folder 44, Item 1-2)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- outline, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 44, Item 3)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 44, Item 4)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 44, Item 5-7)
  - Stück -- notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 44, Item 8)
  - "Kriegsautoren" -- notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 44, Item 9)
  - Pat -- notes, circa 1932 (Box 55, Folder 44, Item 10)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 44, Item 11)
  - Kleiner Roman -- notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 44, Item 12)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 45, Item 1)
  - Pat -- notes, circa 1932 (Box 55, Folder 46, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 46, Item 2)
  - Tristan and Isolde -- notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 46, Item 3)
  - "Der Orion" -- notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 46, Item 4)
  - Station am Horizont / Station at the Horizon -- outline, circa 1927-1928 (Box 55, Folder 46, Item 5)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 47, Item 1-3)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- annotated working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 55, Folder 47, Item 4-5)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 48, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 48, Item 2)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- annotated outline, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 48, Item 3)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- plan, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 48, Item 4)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- annotated notes, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 48, Item 5)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 48, Item 6)
  - "Novellenbuch" -- notes, undated (Box 56, Folder 48, Item 7)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 48, Item 8)
  - Schneider - Wibbel -- notes, undated (Box 56, Folder 48, Item 9)
  - "Kennt ihr die große Schwermut des Trinkers" -- notes, undated (Box 56, Folder 48, Item 10)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 2)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- synopsis, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 3)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- character and scene plan, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 4)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 5-9)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- synopsis and character plan, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 10)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- synopsis, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 11)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 12)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- scene plan and synopsis, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 13)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- plot summary, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 14)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 15)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 16)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 17)
  - Station am Horizont / Station at the Horizon -- working manuscript, circa 1927-1928 (Box 56, Folder 49, Item 18)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 50, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 50, Item 2)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 51, Item 1-2)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- clean copy, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 51, Item 3)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 51, Item 4)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- notes, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 51, Item 5)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 52, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 53, Item 1)
  - Pat -- notes, circa 1932 (Box 56, Folder 53, Item 2)
  - Tessiner Tagebuch -- notes, circa 1931 (Box 56, Folder 53, Item 3)
  - Drama nach Capek -- notes, undated (Box 56, Folder 53, Item 4)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 56, Folder 53, Item 5-7)
  - Pat -- working manuscript, circa 1932 (Box 56, Folder 54, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 57, Folder 55, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 57, Folder 56, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 57, Folder 57, Item 1)
  - Drei Kameraden / Three Comrades -- working manuscript, circa 1936 (Box 57, Folder 58, Item 1)